

Aasiya Fazal

UI / UX Designer

16 The Stables, Birmingham

+44 7515 476449

My Portfolio

Profile

I am an aspiring UI/UX Designer passionate about the key role of design in bridging the gap between technology's potential to transform health and social care and the realisation of this in the form of better health and wellbeing outcomes. I am due to complete a part time UI/UX course in November 2022, having done this alongside working in the NHS throughout COVID and the aftermath. With a portfolio of 4 projects and UI/UX internship experience at Cancer Research UK and a health start up called Healum, my experience is limited. However, having left my NHS job in May to pursue a career in this field, I am confident that I will excel with my determination, commitment to quality and versatility shown consistently in my 4+ years professional experience within private, public and non profit organisations.

Design Skills

User Interviews and Surveys User Research and Competitor Analysis **User Personas** Workshop Facilitation **User Journey Mapping** Wireframing and Prototyping **User Testing** Layout, Typography and Style Guides UI / Visual Design

Education

June 2020 - Nov 2022

CareerFoundry

Part time UI/UX course during which 4 projects have been completed from start to finish.

Sept 2019 - Oct 2021 Birmingham University Part time Postgraduate Diploma in Health Leadership, **Distinction**.

Durham University Oct 2013 - June 2017

Bachelor of Science in Business, Computer Science and Economics, First Class Honours.

MIRO

HTML

HTML

Skills



MURAL

C55

3

CSS





PYTHON

JAVA



SQL

Project Management Skills

Developing Business Cases and SOPs **Process Flow Mapping Project Timelines Project Progress Tracking** Risk Management Stakeholder Management

Data Analysis Skills

Intermediate SQL Advanced Microsoft Excel Power Query

Employment

Oct 2021 - May 2022

Oncology Deputy Service Manager at Royal Orthopaedic Hospital

Supported effective collaboration between various teams involved in the sarcoma cancer pathway; improvements to patient experience were achieved through co-creation and implementation of iterative changes together. In addition, a significant backlog of over 1000 clinical letters was successfully cleared through coordinating efforts to address bottlenecks in the process with key stakeholders. Alongside this, I directly managed a total of eleven staff and recruited to multiple vacancies within the team.

OFFICE 365

June 2021 - Sept 2021

User Experience Intern at Healum

Led the user discovery process to understand how the company's app could be tailored to people with Diabetes and Obesity. This involved: recruiting participants using a wide variety of communication channels, planning and delivering user interviews and focus group sessions and producing a final report; this included key themes and user stories for proposed new features. This research inspired <u>WEllnUS</u>, a health and wellbeing app within my portfolio.

Sept 2019 - June 2021

NHS Leadership Scheme in Wolverhampton

Successfully adapted to a wide variety of work under the pressurised COVID landscape. One of my key achievements was organising and facilitating workshops and process mapping activities between key health and social care stakeholders to operationalise the National hospital discharge policy. Another was creating a digital literacy telephone survey, coordinating its completion with over 400 individuals aged 60+ and producing an infographic which I presented at Board level.

July 2019 - Aug 2019

Summer Intern in Technology at Cancer Research UK

This internship was my first insight into a UI/UX career. I received an Employee Appreciation for facilitating user lab testing on an Alexa quiz prototype. I also led a project to rejuvenate CRUK's Technology recruitment page. This involved: leading workshops around content prioritisation, interviewing employees and using storytelling techniques to create team profiles.

Oct 2017 - June 2019

Technology Associate at KPMG

Received four Encore Awards for my commitment to delivering high quality work and consistently excelling at fulfilling an experienced professional role on projects. My achievements included: analysing IT customer satisfaction for a client and presenting the findings to their IT Leadership team, supporting an IT control redesign project in Amsterdam for one of the largest travel companies in the world and creating a project status dashboard for a client under a pressurised deadline.